Thank y'all!
谢谢大家!
This is going to be a motivational speech.
接下来的演讲将会非常鼓舞人心,
Because --
因为 ——
imagine my motivation standing between this strong, healthy crowd ...
想象一下，我的动力正处在 这个强健的观众群
and lunch.
和午餐之间。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
So ...
所以......
I'm @Falkvinge on Twitter.
我推特账号是@Falkvinge，
Feel free to quote me if I say something memorable, stupid, funny, whatever.
若我在演讲中说了些有意义的、愚蠢的、 或有趣的内容，不论是什么请放心引用。
I love seeing my name on Twitter.
我喜爱看到我的名字出现在推特上。
So ...
所以，
Hi! I'm Rick.
嘿，我是瑞克，
I'm a politician.
我是一个政客。
I'm sorry.
非常抱歉。
How many in here have heard of the Swedish Pirate Party before?
你们中有多少之前听说过 瑞典海盗党？
Let's see a show of hands.
让我们看看有多少人举手。
OK, that's practically everybody.
好吧，基本上每个人 都有听说过，
Probably due to the fact that we are Sweden's neighbor.
也许是因为我们是 瑞典的邻居。
I frequently ask how many have heard of any other political party
我常常问人们是否听说过 任何其它党派，
and there's always just scattered hands in the audience
在观众中只是零零星星几个人。
compared to this first question which is one-half to two-thirds.
相比较，刚刚的第一个问题 有一半到三分之二的人举手。
This is actually the first time ever that does not match.
真的挺不一样的。
It was practically everybody.
几乎所有人都举手了。
So, for those who haven't heard of us:
那么，对于那些没有听说过我们的，
well, the Pirate Party, we love the net.
我们海盗党，我们喜爱网络。
We love copying and sharing, and we love civil liberties.
我们喜爱拷贝和分享 而且我们热爱公民自由。
For that, some people call us pirates.
因为那些原因， 有些人把我们叫做海盗（盗版）。
Probably in an attempt to make us bow our heads and feel shame.
也许是想有意羞辱我们， 让我们站不直腰板。
That didn't work very well.
但对我们却没有起到什么作用。
We decided to stand tall about it instead.
我们决定站直腰板，
And so in 2006, I founded a new political party.
所以，在2006年 我创立了一个新的政党，
I led it for its first five years.
开始的五年，我引领着这个党。
And the European elections, the last European elections,
在最近几次欧洲选举中，
we became the largest party
我们变成了最大的
and the most coveted youth demographic, sub-30.
和最受30岁以下的 年轻人欢迎的党派。
And what's interesting is we did that
我们用了不到竞争者1%的预算
on less than one percent of the competition's budget.
做出了这个成绩。
We had a campaign budget total of 50,000 euros.
我们的竞选总预算是5万欧元。
They had six million between them -- and we beat them.
他们有6百万欧元， 我们战胜了他们。
That gave us a cost efficiency advantage of over two orders of magnitude.
我们的成本效率优势 是其他党派的两个数量级。
And I'm gonna share the secret recipe of how we did that.
现在我将要分享 我们的成功秘笈。
We developed swarm methodologies.
我们发展了集群智能方法。
And they can be applied to any business or social cause.
它们可以应用于任何商业或 社会问题上。
Well, almost any --
好吧，几乎是“任何”，
there's a small asterisk by the end,
“任何”上打着一个小星号，
and I'll get to that in just a minute.
我一会儿将给予解释。
But applying these --
但是应用这些－－
and we've done this dozens of times, we know that this works.
我们实践了这个方法许多次， 它是非常有效的。
We've put two people in the European Parliament,
我们的两位成员已入驻欧洲议会，
we have 45 people in various German state parliaments,
我党在德国各个州立议会中 已有45名议员，
we're in the Icelandic parliament, the Czech senate,
我们在冰岛议会，捷克参议院，
many, many, many more, local councils --
在很多，很多地方议会 生根发芽。
and, as said, we've spread to 70 countries.
我党已经扩展到了70个国家。
And that's not bad for a political movement
对一个成立不到十年的政治运动来说，
that hasn't even been around for a decade.
这个成绩不算坏。
So today we're going to talk a bit about --
所以今天，我们要讨论的是：
how people are motivated to be part of change,
人们是如何被鼓舞参与变革，
to be part of something bigger than themselves.
投身于大于自身的运动中。
And how you can channel this into an organization
以及你该如何把这种精神 引导到你的组织中，
that harnesses this great power of wanting to make the world a better place.
善用“让世界变得更美好” 这思想的巨大力量。
And in the end, come out a little on the better.
最后，不断得出更好的结果。
When I speak to businesspeople, I frequently make them very upset
当我和商人们交谈时， 当我提出与其相异的观点，
when I contradict them
他们会特别生气。
and say that no, your employees are not your most valuable asset.
我告诉他们说，不，你的雇员 不是你最宝贵的资产。
Your most valuable asset is the thousands of people
你最宝贵的资产 是成千上万的
who want to work for you for free.
想为你免费工作的人。
And you don't let them.
你还不让他们。
They get very upset about that.
他们对此感到非常不安。
A swarm is a congregation of tens of thousands of volunteers
集群由成千上万的志愿者组成，
that have chosen of their own will to converge on a common goal.
他们自愿地聚焦在 一个共同的目标上。
There's this "Futurama" quote:
“飞出个未来”里面有一句台词：
"When push comes to shove, you gotta do what you love --
“到了紧要关头， 你必须做你喜欢做的事，
even if it's not a good idea."
即使那不是个好主意。”
(Laughter)
（笑声）
I mean, seriously, what kind of idiot thinks
说真的， 什么样的蠢蛋会认为
they can change the world by starting a political party?
他们可以通过建立一个 党派来改变世界？
(Laughter)
（笑声）
This kind of idiot, apparently.
我这样的蠢蛋，很明显。
But it works!
但这竟然行得通！
What you need to do is to put a stake in the ground.
你要做的是迈出第一步。
You need to announce your goal.
你需要宣告你的目标。
Just say, "I want to accomplish this."
就说，“我想要完成这个。”
I'm going to do this.
我要去达到这个目标。
And it doesn't need to be very costly.
这不一定会很费钱。
My announcement was just two lines in a chat channel.
我的宣言仅仅是在一个 聊天频道里的两行话。
"Hey, look, the Pirate Party has its website up now after New Year's."
“嘿，看，海盗党在新年后 有了自己的网站。”
And the address.
并附上网址。
That was all the advertising I ever did.
那是我所做的全部广告。
The next time I had several hundred activists wanting to work with us.
一下子就有了几百名积极分子 想要和我们合作。
When you provide such a focus point,
当你提供了一个如此有凝聚力的点，
a swarm intelligence emerges.
集群智能就出现了。
When people can rally to a flag.
人们可以团结在一面旗帜下。
And that's what gives you this two orders of magnitude of cost efficiency.
这些可以为你提高两个 数级量的成本效率。
It's a huge advantage --
这是一个巨大的优势——
you're running circles around all the legacy organizations.
你大大超越了所有传统的组织。
And there are four goals that need to be fulfilled in your goal
你的目标需要实现四项标准，
in order for this to work.
它才可以实现。
These four criteria are that your goal must be:
你的目标必须要符合这四个标准：
tangible, credible, inclusive and epic.
切实，可信， 包容，以及伟大。
Let's take a look at them: It needs to be tangible.
让我们看看这些： 你的目标必须是切实的。
A lot of people say,
有许多人说，
"Well, you know, we should make the world a better place,"
“我们应该把世界变得更好。”
or, "Yeah, we should all feel good now."
或者，“我们现在应该感觉很好。”
Not going to work.
这些不可行。
You need a binary.
你需要有分明的调理。
Are we there yet, or are we not there yet?
我们成功了? 还是没有达成目标？
It needs to be credible.
你的目标必须是可信的。
Somebody seeing the project plan that you're posting needs to see
你发出的项目计划 需要让人看到
that, yes, this project plan will take us
它可以把我们
from where we are to where we want to be.
从原地带引到 我们想达到的地方。
You need to break it down into subgoals
你必须把你的目标切分成
that each by themselves are seen as doable,
可付诸实践的子目标，
and when you add the subgoals together,
当达成了所有子目标时，
we've gone to where we want.
我们就到了我们想去的地方。
It needs to be --
它必须——
and this is where it gets exciting in terms of working swarmwise --
这就是集群智能让人兴奋的地方——
it needs to be inclusive.
它必须是包容的。
Anybody who sees this project plan needs to immediately say,
任何看到项目计划的人会立刻说，
"I want to do this -- and there's my spot!"
“我想要做这个，那是我的位置！”
And they will be able to jump right into the project
他们能够立马付诸实践
and start working on it without asking anybody's permission.
并在无需任何人许可的 情况下开始实施计划。
And that is exactly what'll happen.
那正是将要发生的。
And, last but not least, it needs to be epic.
最后，你的目标必须是伟大的。
It needs to energize people. It needs to electrify people.
它必须使人感到激情。 它必须令人迸出火花。
Shoot for the moon!
向月球出发！
On second thought, don't shoot for the moon,
现在想想，不要向月球出发，
we've already been there -- shoot for Mars!
我们已经到过那个地方了—— 向火星出发！
(Laughter)
（笑声）
In contrast,
与此相反，
you will never be able to get a volunteer swarm forming
一个志愿集群永远不会聚集
around making the most correct tax audit ever.
去完成最正确的税务审计。
Doesn't electrify people. Go to Mars.
它不会使人迸出火花的， 向火星出发！
A lot of people kind of balk at the obstacles.
很多人在障碍面前会望而却步。
We're going to climb a huge mountain.
我们要去攀爬一个巨大的山峰。
So how do you motivate people to do that?
那么，你如何鼓舞人们？
Well, it turns out that obstacles are not the problem.
结果证明，障碍不是问题。
Not knowing the obstacles is the problem.
不知道障碍才是问题。
If you know how high the mountain is,
如果你知道山有多高，
you know exactly what it takes to scale it.
你知道去测量它需要什么。
We know exactly how far away Mars is and what it takes to get there.
我们确切地知道火星有多远 以及如何去那里。
If you can plan it like a project,
如果你像一个项目一样去规划它，
you can plan what resources you need
你可以计划你需要的资源，
and you can execute it, exactly like a project.
你就可以执行它，就像执行项目一样。
Let's see: we're going to Mars,
让我们看看：我们要去火星，
we need two dozen volunteer rocket scientists,
我们需要24个火箭科学家志愿者，
one dozen volunteer metallurgists,
12个冶金学家志愿者，
some crazy dude who will mix rocket fuel in his backyard
还有些能在自家的后院 混合火箭燃料的疯子，
and so on.
以及诸如此类。
When you can list the resources, you know what you need to get there.
当你能列出资源清单， 你知道到达那你需要什么。
When you know what you need to get there, you can go there.
当你知道需要什么才能到达那， 你就可以去那。
And the next thing is to encourage this development of a swarm intelligence,
然后下一个事情是鼓励 这个集群智慧的发展，
which is where the cost efficiency comes in.
这正是成本效率显现的地方。
There's a TED Talk on motivation that debunks that we work for money,
有一个TED的演讲 打破了我们为钱工作这一谎言，
and it presents science on how we're really motivated by three things,
它用科学证明了 当我们面对大型的创意性工作时，
in terms of larger creative tasks,
当我们投身于比自己更大的号召时，
when we work for something bigger than ourselves.
我们会被三个因素激励。
We work for autonomy, mastery and purpose.
我们为自主权，掌控，和意义工作。
We've covered purpose already.
我们已经讲过意义了。
As in, working for something bigger, tangible, credible, inclusive and epic.
就是为一些更远大的，切实的 可信的，包容的和伟大的事情工作。
So, where that motivation talk ends,
那个 TED 演讲结束时，
what it doesn't answer is,
它没有回答的是，
how do you build an organization that harnesses this motivational power.
你如何利用这种激励力量 来建立一个组织。
And this is where working swarmwise comes in,
这正是集群参与的意义，
this is where swarm intelligence comes in.
这就是集群智能起作用的地方。
Turns out that there are three factors that you optimize for --
我们发现，有三个需要你去优化的因素，
and each of these are in complete opposite to what you learn at a business school.
每一个都和你在 商学院学到的完全相反。
But it works.
但是它们是可行的。
We know it works.
我们知道它们非常有效。
We have people in many, many parliaments to prove it.
我党成功进入 许多议会的成员就可以证明这点。
Those three factors are: speed, trust and scalability.
这三个因素是：速度，信任和延展性。
We optimize for speed by cutting bottlenecks out of the loop,
我们通过清除回路中的瓶颈 来优化速度，
cutting them out of the decision loop.
将它们从决策过程中去除。
That means cutting yourself out of the decision loop,
这意味着把自己排除在 决策回路之外，
which can be hard.
这会很艰难。
But you've got to communicate your vision so passionately, so strongly,
但你必须充满激情地把你的想法 与他人交流，
that everybody knows what the goal is
让每个人都知道目标是什么,
and can find something, some step
让他们可以发现一些事情， 一些步骤
that takes the movement just a little closer to that goal.
一起让这个运动一点点靠近那个目标。
And when tens of thousands of people do that on a weekly basis,
当成千上万人每周都这样做时，
you become an unstoppable force.
你就成为一股不可阻止的力量。
We had a three-person rule in our organization,
我们组织里有一条三人原则，
saying that if three self-identified volunteers in the movement
如果有三名自认志愿者
were in agreement that something was good for the movement,
都一致认为一件事对运动有好处，
they had the green light from the highest office
那么，最高层会开绿灯，
to go ahead and act in the name of the organization,
让他们以组织的名义 来继续推进和行动，
including spending resources.
其中包括使用组织资源。
When you talk about this kind of empowerment
当你和传统的生意人
to traditional businesspeople,
讨论这样一种授权时，
they think you belong in a zoo.
他们认为你是动物园来的。
But you know what?
但是你知道吗？
I led this organization for five years,
我领导这个组织5年了，
there were 50,000 registered members
有50,000注册成员
and many, many more anonymous activists.
并且很多，更多都是匿名积极分子。
It was not abused once.
它一次也没有被滥用。
Everybody had the key to the treasure chest.
每个人有通向宝箱的钥匙，
It was not abused one single time.
它没有被滥用过一次。
Turns out when you give people the keys to the castle,
当你给人们城堡的钥匙时，
and look them in the eye and say, "I trust you,"
并看着他们的眼睛说“我信任你”，
they step up to the plate.
他们全力以赴起来。
And that's a beautiful thing to see happen.
这是一件美妙的事情。
Obviously, not everything went according to plan,
显然，不是每件事情都会按计划发生，
but that's a different thing.
但那是另外一回事。
We made mistakes. We should expect mistakes.
我们会犯错误， 我们也应该预期到错误。
If you're pioneering something, that means you must, by definition,
如果你在某些事情上领先， 那意味着你一定
venture into the unknown.
要冒险进入未知领域。
When you're trying the unknown, some things won't go as planned.
当你尝试未知事物时， 有些事情就不会按照计划来。
That's part of the definition of venturing into the unknown.
这就是冒险进入未知世界的定义。
To find the great, you must allow mistakes to happen.
要追寻伟大，你必须允许错误发生。
So you must communicate that we expect some things to go wrong
所以我们必须传达 我们会预期到问题的出现，
to create a risk-positive environment.
创造一个将风险积极化的环境。
Therefore we optimize for iteration speed.
因此我们优化迭代速度。
Meaning that we try, we fail, we try again, we fail faster,
意味着我们尝试，我们失败， 我们再尝试，我们败得更快，
we fail better, we try again, we fail better again.
我们败得更好，我们再次尝试， 我们再次败得更好。
Maybe after we've tried 15 times, we've mastered some specific subject,
也许在我们尝试了15次后， 我们掌握到了特定技能，
so you want to minimize the time it takes to try those 15 times.
所以你需要缩短这15次尝试的时间。
We optimize on trust. We encourage diversity.
我们优化信任， 我们鼓励多样性。
You need to communicate your vision so strongly
你需要强烈传达你的愿景，
so that everybody can translate it into their own context
这样每个人都可以把 它转变为自己的理解，
because language is an incredibly strong
因为语言是一种非常强大的
inclusionary and exclusionary social marker.
兼具包含性和排他性的社会标志。
This one-brand-fits-all message --
那些所谓的适用于任何企业的讯息，
forget it!
忘掉它！
That's what they teach you at business school -- it doesn't work.
那是商业院教你的东西——它行不通。
Or at least, it doesn't give you the cost-efficiency advantage
或者至少，它不会给你 带来集群工作的
of working swarmwise.
成本效率优势。
This leads to a lot of different approaches tried in parallel
这会引发许多不同的方法在
in different social groups
不同的社会群体中并行地尝试，
who try out different methods of working toward the goal.
尝试不同的方法来实现目标。
Some of them will work
其中有些行得通，
but in order to find the great ones, you need this diversity.
但是为了发现最好的方法， 你需要多样化。
And you need to communicate that we need that diversity.
你需要沟通，我们需要多样性。
If somebody on this side does not understand
如果这边有人不明白
what those guys are doing,
那边的人在干啥，
that's OK because we all trust each other to work for the better of the movement.
这是可接受的，因为我们相信 彼此都是为了更好的运动工作。
And it's OK that I don't understand their social context.
我不明白他们的社会背景 也是可以的。
I'm not expected to -- I understand my social context.
我不期望－ 我明白我的社会背景。
I contribute with something I know.
我贡献我知道的东西。
Make people aware of this diversity.
让人们意识到多样性，
Finally, scalability. Get feet on the ground.
最后，规模化的，脚踏实地。
Again, in business school, they teach you to use a lean organization.
再一次，在商学院，他们教授你 使用精简的组织结构。
Forget that.
忘掉它。
Just scale up the organization from the get-go.
一开始就扩大组织规模。
Start with 10,000 empty boxes and an org chart
从10,000个空盒子和一张覆盖到
covering down to every minor city.
每个小城市的组织结构图开始。
When you have lots and lots of small responsibilities
当您在这样的框架中有
in such a scaffolding that supports the swarm,
很多很多小的职责来支持群体，
supports the activists,
支持积极分子时，
you'll find that these boxes in the org charts
您会发现组织结构图中的这些框
are getting filled in quite rapidly,
被很快地填满，
and they start to get filled in beyond your horizon
并且它们开始在你的视野之外
with people you've never heard of.
被你从未听说过的人填满。
And so, this swarm keeps growing to tens of thousands of people,
于是，这个群体持续增长到 成千上万的人，
each taking on something small with very, very decentralized mandate
每个人都承担着组织一些很小，很小，
to act on the organization.
非常分散的任务。
And this is when a swarm intelligence emerges.
这就是集群智能出现的时候。
This is when you have this beehive logic where everybody knows what's to be done.
你就有了蜂箱逻辑， 每个人都知道该做什么。
Everybody is taking their own small steps towards it.
每个人在超着目标迈出 他们自己的一小步。
So the swarm starts to act as a coherent organism.
所以集群开始表现得像 一个连贯的有机体。
And it's amazing to watch.
这是一件很不可思议的事。
This is when you're awarded by the cost-efficiency advantage
这就是在和你的竞争者相比时，
over your competitors
你的成本效益好于对方
by two orders of magnitude.
两个数量级。
Two orders of magnitude.
This is not just a silver bullet.
这不仅仅是个灵丹妙药。
So we've been talking a lot about the big picture today.
所以我们今天谈论了 很多大方向的东西。
You can use these swarm methods for a lot of stuff.
你可以将集群的原理 运用在很多事情上
Do you want to change the world?
你想要改变世界吗？
Do you want to bring clean water to a billion people?
你想要给数亿人带去 干净的饮用水吗？
Teach three billion people to read?
你想要教授数亿人读书吗？
Maybe you're into social change;
也许你想要社会变革；
you want to introduce unconditional basic income.
你想要引进无条件的基本收入。
Or maybe you want to take humanity to Mars.
或者也许你想把人类带到火星上去，
You can do this using these methods.
你可以用这些方法做这些事情。
You can do this.
你可以做到。
It's about leadership.
这事关领导力。
It's about deciding what you want to do and telling it to the world.
这关于决定你想做什么， 然后告诉全世界。
Because no matter whether you think you can or cannot change the world,
因为无论你认为你 能不能改变世界，
no matter whether you think you can or cannot change the world,
无论你认为能不能改变世界，
you are probably right.
你有可能是对的。
So one question I want everybody here to ask themselves today
所以，一个我想今天在坐的 各位问自己的问题是
is the observation that change doesn't just happen, somebody makes it happen --
改变不是就那样发生的， 是有人使它发生的——
do you want to be that person?
你想要成为那个人吗？
Do you want to be that person?
你想不想成为那个人？
And then one last thing:
然后最后一件事：
There's one component more that's required to work swarmwise
还有一件集群工作所需要的组件
that I haven't mentioned yet.
我还没有提及。
And that is fun.
那就是乐趣。
This goes beyond just enjoying your job,
这不仅仅是享受你的工作，
this goes beyond having a pinball machine in the office.
这不止是在办公室 放置一个弹球机器。
Because this is actually required to succeed in a swarmwise scenario.
这对于集群智能的起效 是必须要具备的。
This is required to succeed
这是要达到两个数量级
to get that cost-efficiency advantage of two orders of magnitude.
的成本效益优势所必须的。
For the reason that you need to attract volunteers.
出于吸引志愿者的缘故。
And people, in this aspect, are rather predictable.
以及人，在这方面说 是非常可预测的。
People will go to other people who are having fun.
人们会找那些玩的开心的人。
In contrast, they will walk an extra mile to avoid people who are not having fun.
反之，他们会尽量避开那些 不会享受有趣事物的人。
So, having fun is more than just having a pinball machine in the office.
所以，享受乐趣不仅仅是 在办公室放个弹珠机器。
It's an absolute and unavoidable requirement
这绝对是集群工作，
for organizational and operational success when you're working swarmwise.
组织和运营成功不可避免的要求。
So, in summary --
所以，总结一下——
a recipe for a swarm organization
一个使用这些激励方法
using these motivational methods to a huge competitive advantage.
的蜂群组织来获得 巨大竞争优势的秘诀。
Your goal: it needs to be tangible, credible, inclusive and epic.
你的目标：它必须是具体的， 可信的，包容性的和伟大的。
Your organization needs to be optimized for speed, trust and scalability.
你的组织需要优化速度，信任和规模。
You need to enjoy yourselves.
你必须享受你自己。
And that will reward you
它就会以两个数量级
with two orders of magnitude of cost-efficiency advantage.
的成本效益优势给你回报。
Thank you.
谢谢！
(Applause)
（鼓掌）